Akshitha Ravi

945-249-0421 | akshitharavi01@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/akshitharavi

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have always been interested in computer science and after completing my computer science degree I have chosen to specialize in cyber security. Cyber security is very important and an essential part of any organization. I want to be part of a cyber team to help with the continued challenge of protecting against bad actors and growing my career.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Cybersecurity, Technology, and Policy -

The University of Texas at Dallas

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science -

Panimalar Engineering College, India

SKILLS

• Wireshark/Nmap/Burp Suite

• Identity Access Management

• DNS Monitoring

MS Office Suite

• OWASP Top 10

NIST SP 800-53

• C & Java

• HTML/CSS

VMWare

August 2024

August 2022 Grade: 8.58/10.0

Grade: 3.73/4.0

• Eclipse

• SQL

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Java Intern, The Shiash Infotech - October 2021 - December 2021

- In this role I conducted Java code reviews, identifying, and resolving software issues before deployment this helped increase the deployment frequency of applications and this also resulted in a more robust and stable codebase.
- I had to be self disciplined with my time management to ensure that multiple tasks got completed to meet tight project delivery deadlines to ensure smooth project progression.

Cyber Security Intern, Bank of Montreal (BMO) - August 2023 - December 2023

- In this role I conducted DNS monitoring looking for fraudulent websites being registered ~5,000 every month, were detected and mitigated/closed reducing the potential threats to the business.
- Assisted in the implementation of intake processes, resulting in 40% improved response time for IT service requests.
- Improved efficiency by reducing the number of IT service requests received via Cherwell Service Management, resulting in a 20% overall service efficiency gain.

ACADEMIC PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Scrutinizing Manifold Stipulations by Linear Kernel, Cybernetics - December 2021 - July 2022

Completed a project that would demonstrate a potential 40% increase in the efficiency of a car manufacturer using real-time high dimensional data.

Personality Prediction through CV analysis, Web Page - May 2021 - September 2021

Designed and implemented a web application using HTML, PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript, that analyzed the five big personality traits – Openness, Extraversion, Neuroticism, Agreeableness & Conscientiousness,

Pattern Lock Authentication with in-built Fingerprint sensor for android - July 2021 - August 2022

Undertook research on the android authentication and created/published a scholar paper in the 5th International Conference on Intelligent Computing Iconic 2022.

Akshitha Ravi

945-249-0421 | akshitharavi01@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/akshitharavi

CERTIFICATIONS

- Programming with C and C++
- International Workshop on Ethical Hacking
- Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate
- (ISC)2 Certified in Cybersecurity
- CompTIA Security+

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Cyber Security Fundamentals
- Digital Forensics and Management
- Cognitive Psychology in Cybersecurity
- Data Privacy and Security
- Legal Aspects of Cyber Security Ethics
- Cyber Security Analytics
 & Malware Analysis
- Cyber Security Policy
- Governance and Auditing Essentials for Cybersecurity
- Cyber Physical Systems and Critical Infrastructure Security